Hey... What's that song?
Cut! Cut!
Who let that creep in here?
Spongers!
Throw him the hell out of here!
What do we pay you for?
SERGEI BODROV
-Your name?
- Bagrov.
Danila Sergeyevich.
Born 1975.
Station Street, 22.
- Place of work?
- Haven't finished being demobbed yet.
-Where did you serve?
- In the army.
-Want to work for us?
- No.
You broke their security guy's arm.
And nearly took his eye out.
If you'd been drunk,
I'd have arrested you.
Get outta here!
If you don't get a job within a week,
I'll put you on probation.
VIKTOR SUKHORUKOV
I really broke his arm?
No. Just dislocated it.
And that guy who was screaming?
Who is he?
The director.
-And what was that song?
- ''Wings'' by Nautilus.
SVETLANA PISMICHENKO
Sergei Bagrov,
born 1942,
...repeat convictions for burglary.
He was killed in a prison camp
in January '82.
He was my classmate.
YURI KUZNETSOV
Do you have ''Wings'' by Nautilus?
The CD?
Whadda you want? Get out of here,
or I'll call the police.
VYACHESLAV BUTUSOV
You could at least chop wood
ratherthan sticking your neck out.
Would have been betterto stay
in the army.
Here they'll probably kill you,
idiot.
Always turning on that metal of yours.
You'll croak in prison
like your good-for-nothing father.
The only hope I have
is my little Viktor.
He's a big man there, you know,
in Leningrad.
Just look at these. So little.
How cute you all were.
-Just look.
- I've seen them.
Take another look.
You had better go to your brother
in Leningrad.
I'll die soon, you know,
and he's to you like father now.
This is your blood.
The closest person to you
in this world.
My little Viktor.
BROTHER
If you haven't seen Moscow,
you haven't seen much.
The Chechen was released.
We need to take him out.
He grabbed the whole market.
Says it was his.
He's collecting from our spots.
At the meet we agreed all peaceful,
like our people don't want war.
But he and Paramon are close...
The Chechen's going down!
In short, fifteen.
You know me. My prices are fair.
Fifteen...
That's good money, of course,
but forthe Chechen...
With him I'm risking my skull.
- How much?
- Twenty. And ten up front.
You get a week for prepwork.
Two.
The Tatar's becoming a wiseguy.
He took a lot up front.
You guys hang up at the market day
and night, and keep out of sight.
Bite off more than you can chew
and you wind up in the zoo.
- Do you have ''Wings'' by Nautilus?
- No. They go quickly.
But you stop in again. We should get
another shipment.
- Have you anything else?
- Of course.
Here's ''Titanic on the Fontanka''
with Grebenschikov.
And this is ''Ten-year Report''
Their best songs covered by friends.
How much they cost?
This one's 75,800. The other one's
78,000.
Well, what we selling, wino?
You got watches?
Well, my cut's fifty now.
From you, you fucking worm, I said!
And what did you think?
Taxes.
- But I haven't sold anything yet!
- I'm confiscating the goods.
But, sonny, ljust...
I haven't sold anything yet.
- I haven't sold anything!
-What's the difference?
The city?
The city's a frightening force.
And the biggerthe city,
the stronger it is.
It sucks you in.
Only the strong can climb out.
And even so...
-What's your name?
- Hoffman.
-What are you, a Jew?
- I'm German.
Oh... I'm not wild about Jews...
-And Germans?
- Germans? They're okay.
-What's the difference?
-Why you badgering me about it?
-Where have you taken me?
- My homeland.
My ancestors lie here.
Sit down.
- Here.
- Hold on.
What?
I brought a present for my brother.
I guess it wasn't to be.
Oh, gimme some of that...
She's a doll.
Hey, girl, what's your name?
Tickets, please.
No ticket.
Your tickets, please.
Listen, you Russian or what?
I'm saying to you in Russian:
no ticket.
Then pay the fine, please.
What fine, huh?
I'm an invalid.
You pay the fine or show me
your ticket.
Hey, take a load off your feet.
Sit down.
Well, if you haven't got tickets,
then you have to pay the fine.
Hey, don't you understand?
Come on, come on.
Pay the fine!
Brother, don't kill me!
The money,
take it all, take it!
Don't kill me, brother!
You're not my brother,
you blackassed worm!
- How much is the fine?
- Seven.
Run!
Hey, guys!
It's not ''Nora'', it's ''Norah''.
In short, you know, to get there
you've got to...
Bye!
Man, oh man, that's such a cool
Walkman! Let me listen.
Why you blasting this crap?
Have you got anything decent?
-Are you deaf or something?
- No.
Your Walkman's fine,
but you're dressed like a pig.
You got any acid?
Or dough?
Got any dough?
- No.
I'm Kat.
You can always find me here.
If you get some money, come here
and we'll get stoned. Well, later!
It's open!
On your knees! Hands out!
I'm looking for my brother.
Viktor Bagrov. He lived here.
I'm his younger brother.
Been in Leningrad two days.
My mom gave me his address:
Moika 1, apartment 8.
Well, hello, brother!
It's not Leningrad,
but St. Petersburg.
St. Pete's, for short.
A beautiful city, but a province.
Got to go to Moscow.
All the power's there.
I'll scrape it a little more here,
and then to Moscow.
- How's mom?
- Okay.
Here, she sent you this.
Come on, drink. I still got
some business to take care of.
This'll hold you over for awhile.
Get some nice clothes,
rent an apartment or a room.
Nothing over a hundred for now
and then we'll see.
- How was the army?
- Okay.
Mom wrote that you were in the war.
Nah. I sat things out at HQ.
I was a clerk.
Can you shoot?
Yeah, they took us out
to the shooting range.
Hello.
Do you have ''Wings'' by Nautilus?
Well, just give me what you got.
He's an ex-Chechen terrorist.
They've moved into St. Pete
from Moscow too.
Grabbing up everything, brother.
I already told you about it.
Took this market.
Now he's squeezing Russians out.
And I got a piece of the action there.
So he came down hard. He knows we're
weak now, so he's strangling us.
He bought off everyone there.
And killed the ones he didn't buy up.
And so it's my turn, Danny.
If I don't pay...
So it's either him or us.
That's how it is, brother.
He loves walking around the market
during the day.
Inspects his holdings, the creep.
This is the best place.
His bodyguards are always with him:
two or three guerillas.
All darkies. With rods. Beasts.
All in all, the job's not easy.
You size things up and think
how you'll make your exit.
I'd better give the money to you.
Two thousand bucks.
Don't come to my place anymore,
it's dangerous.
If something comes up, give me a ring.
Here's a barrel and a clip.
That's another six hundred.
-We'll settle up later.
- I'll get by.
Hello. It's us.
The Tatar wasn't there.
- How much for potatoes?
- One and a half.
How's business?
Ah, who cares?
Only that thug and his pals are here,
looking for you.
Listen, German. I need a room.
A small one. Downtown.
In a quiet neighborhood.
Ask your people, okay?
Here.
Thanks.
- Did you find your brother?
- I found him.
-Who is it?
- It's me, Zinka. Open up.
Zinka? Who the heck's Zinka?
Get outta here, whore.
Have you lost your fucking mind, old
man? Open up! It's me, Zinka!
What a fool! His brain's rotted!
-What do you want?
- I brought you a lodger.
Get it out!
People walking around...
So, old man, you got all mangy here
without me?
Hey, you, kind sir!
Buy a watermelon.
- Is it good?
- Sure! Look what a beauty!
-Yesterday I ate 7 of them myself.
- Okay.
- How much?
- Only six thousand.
Thanks. Enjoy it!
Lord! What's going on?
There, the guy with the watermelon!
Maybe you need help, huh?
I'm outta here. Keep driving.
I'll find you.
It wasn't the Tatar. A young guy.
He did everything first class.
A real pro.
The Chechen kicked the bucket,
and that guy just walked off.
He hopped in a yellow tram
and was off.
I winged him, the motherfucker.
But the bitch greased Pinecone.
Pinecone? Whacked him dead?
Don't know. They took him
to the hospital.
Why were you shooting
if it wasn't the Tatar?
Well, you know, I...
It's the Tatar we have to pay.
You shit-for-brains!
But that the new guy whacked
Pinecone is fine.
They won't suspect us.
Well, Tatar!..
His life hangs by a thread,
but he thinks about the bread.
We should take you to the hospital.
I can't go to the hospital, German.
It's okay, German...
We'll get through.
Zinka! Zinka!
If I'd met you outside Kursk
in '43...
- Beat it, old fool. What do you want?
- Come here.
Get some more vodka, strong stuff,
and bandages at the drugstore,
and... streptomycin.
And antibiotics.
And get something for Gramps,
so he stops pestering us.
Okay.
You're a smart man, German.
Tell me: what do we live for?
Well, everyone decides himself.
There's this saying:
''What's good forthe Russian
is death for the German.''
I live to disprove this.
Do you have a gal?
What about Zinka?
It's probably 'cause of her
you took a shot in the eye?
Never mind.
You're a good man, German.
They closed the kiosk downstairs.
Why'd you stop? Let's roll.
What's with your face?
My husband.
Maybe I can help?
I'll deal with it.
That fellow-traveller you had
the other day, where's he?
He jumped off.
On the corner of Sredny and 18th.
- He rode for a long time.
-A long time.
Why didn't you call the police?
He's a good shot.
Can't argue with that.
Well, look, if you lied
I'll punish you.
Happy is not the man with money, but
the man whose wife sleeps in his bed.
Good day.
Hey! Where you been? Nautilus
came out with a new disc.
It's called ''Chinapple''.
They've all been snatched up.
But, on the other hand, there's also...
I'll take it.
Tatar? It's me.
We need to meet.
We have some business to discuss.
Who did that to you?
My husband. When he gets drunk...
They were looking for you.
I said that you jumped off on Sredny.
- How's your wound? Healed up?
-Yeah, it's okay.
I feel hungry.
May be we can go to my place?
And your old man?
In the can.
-What's your name?
- Danila.
I'm Sveta.
This is ''play''.
And ''stop'' is here.
You can rewind and fastforward.
And this is volume.
Got it?
- Gimme the telephone.
-What?
- The telephone.
- The neighbors will pick it up.
Gimme the phone! I need to make
a call!
Your husband?
- Come on, tell me about it.
- I don't want to.
Hello.
Hello, brother.
Gimme the money, okay?
Danny! I looked everywhere for you.
Where are you?
Hello, brother? The line's bad.
Call me back: 311-0536. Okay?
Hello, Danny!
Well, brother, what the hell?
Where'd you disappear to?
Is everything okay?
Come on over right now.
Grab some wheels on the double.
No. I'm going to a concert today.
Nautilus is playing.
I'll drop by tomorrow.
Okay, don't pout.
Maybe I'll tell you sometime.
All right, come on, we're late.
- Hi.
-You've turned onto smack?
- Uh-huh.
- I thought you didn't like this music?
- It's just a scene.
l see you got some new threads.
Did you get a hold of some dough?
Tomorrow I'm getting a wad.
I know where to get some cool ganja.
Here, call me.
- Is this your mom?
- No.
Well, okay. Later.
-Who was that little tart?
-An acquaintance.
You did a fine job, brother.
You saved my ass and helped people.
Now only Russians will sell there.
-And Germans?
-What do you mean, Germans?
-Will there be Germans there?
-What kind of Germans?
-You know, Germans.
-Why Germans?
I've got this proposal for you,
brother.
Let's open a firm:
''The Bagrov Brothers''.
How's that sound?
Well, tell me, you like it?
-What will we do?
- Business. Basically everything.
But the main thing is that we've got
a problem. There's competition.
''Roundhead''. That's his nickname.
Huh? It's a surprise.
Well, should I come?
Can we listen to your discs
on that thing?
We can.
-Which button is ''play''?
- The green one.
-What's this?
- The Nautilus anniversary concert.
A rare find. I got it.
There's Shevchuk, Kinchev,
Nastya, everybody here.
Yes?
No, I can't today.
I'm relaxing. Yeah.
I said no!
l haven't got time to haggle with you.
That's it. Bye.
Your husband?
No, that was my coworker.
She asked me to take her shift.
Those assholes, they slipped me
a pirated copy.
Where did you serve?
At HQ.
-Who are you?
- I'm Danila. And who're you?
Me? Pavel Yevgrafovich.
And Sveta... Where's she?
Sveta?
She's not here.
But you, Pavel Yevgrafovich,
listen to me carefully.
You're going to give me the keys now
and forget this address
and telephone number forever.
Ah, fancy pants!
Why you hitting me in the balls?
The keys!
I see you again one more time
and I'll kill you.
We'll see who does who.
Kat? Hi. It's Danila.
Remember, the guy with the Walkman?
You gave me your number
at the concert.
You said when I got some money,
we'd party.
Yeah, I've got money.
Oh, it's you?
And I thought: what Danila?
What Walkman?
Gimme the dough.
Here.
What'll it be? Half dose each?
Should we get wasted?
What they singing about?
What the fuck do you care?
They sing like gods.
I don't like it.
He gets high on Nautilus,
the dickhead.
Your American music is shit.
I said: the music is shit.
And don't you argue.
Yeah, and you too... Soon your
entire America's going to bite it.
We're going to wipe the smiles
off all your fucking faces.
You got it?
-Why you hassling him. He's French.
- Big difference.
- Do you have contraceptives?
-What for?
You think I'm going
to give you money?
Ah, Jean has some.
-What you doing that for?
- So I won't lose my head.
Let's go.
- Hello.
- Danny? Help me out, brother.
I've got sick. You need to roll right
away and deal with it for me.
Behind the Baltic Hotel,
on Basil's Island, at five.
There'll be this Volvo. Two guys.
They'll explain everything.
They ain't having any brains,
and you'll see yourself what's what.
Brother, I ain't got any brains
either. My skull's killing me.
Brother, if you don't help me out,
it's the end of me.
Help me.
This is part of our business.
I can't talk about it on the phone,
Danny.
Take everything with you. Don't
worry about the money. Help me out.
Okay.
Hello, thugs!
We only found the creep yesterday.
Turned out to be tough.
Been hiding for almost six months.
Now he's back,
living with a friend.
l think we should stand inside
the front door and wait for him.
All three of us?
Hey, do you have any aspirin?
No.
There's a back entrance to the flat
and an exit up to the attic.
We can do it there.
Why are there three of us?
Me and Flatiron are together...
Are they packing heat?
And what do you think?
The dough they've swiped.
Ring the bell.
Makar, is that you?
Quiet, creep.
On the floor! On the floor!
-Where is he?
-Who?
You didn't understand, bitch?
He went to the metro, for vodka.
Don't shoot. You don't have to shoot.
There's no one here.
Well, we'll see, creep.
Flatiron, tie him up.
Don't walk by the window.
You got any music?
Got any music?
Hit the floor!
Guys, I probably got the wrong flat.
I probably need the next floor.
It's not him.
Who is he?
-What's your name?
- Stepan.
Don't be afraid, Stepan.
We won't touch you.
You just sit tight
and don't move a muscle.
Okay.
-What do you do?
- I'm a director. For Radio One.
A director? I saw a director once.
He was shooting this video...
They're all fags.
Nobody here's going to lay a finger
on you. I give you my word.
You sit tight.
We're waiting for a comrade of ours.
We'll have a little chat with him,
then let you go right away.
You make a wrong move, bitch,
and I'll shoot you in the eye.
Stepan, you wouldn't have any aspirin?
No? Too bad.
Watch out, I'll take your head off,
bitch!
Say it's your birthday. Your birthday.
It's my birthday.
- How long it takes to walk from
the metro? - Fifteen minutes.
If he's not here in five minutes,
it's all over for you.
Quiet!
- Good evening.
- Is the party here?
- No.
Slava, I told you:
the top floor and on the left.
Oh. Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
Quiet, creep!
Bon appetit!
- Hello, eagles!
- Hi!
-Watch out, don't fall!
- Give me your hand.
- Hello!
- Hey!
What do you want?
Do you have any aspirin?
- My skull is splitting.
-You should drink vodka.
No, I need aspirin.
Well, if that's the case, let's go.
Let me through.
Here, get cured.
Can I sit here a little while?
Of course, sit down.
You wanted to blow?
They nearly took us out.
If I wanted to blow,
I'd have blown.
All right, we'll leave by the back
entrance.
Flatiron, take care of that one.
Wait a minute. I'll do it myself.
Gimme that.
Oh, a pistol.
Quiet, quiet.
We had an agreement.
That's that. It's all over. Let go.
Come on, come on. Calm down.
You see it's okay?
I don't like directors very much.
No, you're okay, a regular guy.
Hey, do you know Butusov?
Yeah?
I like his music very much.
Is it true they put out a new album,
''Chinapple''?
- Do you have it?
-Yes.
Hey, be a pal and let me tape it, huh?
My name's Danila.
You'll help me, okay?
Well, can I go now?
Let's go have a drink.
Zinka!
This is my friend, Stepan.
Well, I'll be going?
Okay.
Come and stop by.
Sorry that it turned out this way.
Why are you staring?
I saved good people.
And that weakling overthere too.
God be your judge.
German, they're over in the crypt
by the fence.
Give them a decent burial.
- Good day!
- Hi!
-Your husband home?
- He's on a business trip.
When hubby's away, the wife does play.
Shall we come in? Standing here's
is not Russian way.
I asked you not to deceive your
husband. It's not Christian.
I really don't know where he lives
and what he's doing.
Everything's clean.
He was here for two days.
He found me himself.
I kicked him out.
I'm telling you the truth.
If you like your honey sweet,
you should like the bees indeed.
Let me go, creeps!
Don't touch me, scum!
Let me go!
Ouch! I'll kill you, bitch!
- Scum!
- Lie down!
I'll kill the motherfucker!
Your people stopped by.
They asked for you.
I really don't know
who you are and where you live.
They didn't believe me.
Their chief had a round mug,
talked in proverbs.
Shall we sing a song?
I'm tone deaf.
Yeah, I understand.
You say he served at HQ?
As a clerk?
First Pinecone, then two more
disappeared.
And now the Mole.
Simple like that.
You live, you learn,
you live and learn.
Yeah. Danny, is that you?
What happened?
Something happened, brother.
You alone?
Good. I'll be there soon
and tell you everything.
He's coming.
-What do you want?
- Gramps, sell me your rifle.
-A million.
- Bring it out.
Give me the money first.
- Dollars!
- There's a million two hundred here.
Drag out all the shells.
Five caliber. For ducks.
You lie here quiet, I'll let you go.
All right. I got it.
Guns on the floor! Hands behind your
heads! Lie down, mugs on the floor!
Viktor, get up.
Don't shoot, brother. Please.
What you saying, brother? Come on,
get up, it's over.
Forgive me, brother.
Don't shoot, please. Don't kill me.
Brother. You're my brother.
You were like a father to me.
I even called you papa.
You remember how I cut my leg
when we went fishing?
You dragged me home,
ten kilometers.
Remember how I got scared of a cat-
fish? And you just laughed at me?
You promised.
I keep my word.
And you tell your people: I'll whack
whoever touches my brother.
Go.
- It was him who betrayed you.
- I know.
- Forgive me, brother.
- Cut it out.
Where's the money?
In his briefcase.
He took everything, the creep.
You go home. To mama.
She's getting old.
Needs help.
Give her the money.
Get a job, with the police.
Uncle Kolya is the chief there,
he was dad's classmate.
They've got an opening.
Don't take the train.
Hitchhike out of the city.
Well, brother? So long.
If God wills it, we'll see each other
sometime.
Did you forget, you piece of shit?
You forgot what I told you?
-You forgot?
- Pavel!
I'll break you of your whoring!
I'll make that fancy pants little
retard of yours eat shit!
Where is he?
Where's that asshole? Huh?
Here I am.
Ah! Mr. Cool's arrived.
Well, brother, how we gonna
split the bitch?
You're not my brother.
Pavel!
Take your hands of it!
Hold on, hold on.
It's okay, Pavel, it's okay.
Quiet, quiet.
It's okay, Pavel.
Sveta!
Come on, shoot!
Kill everybody, come on!
You're the big man here!
What's it cost you to kill a man?
You, a clerk!
- Sveta!
- Get out!
Get me a towel.
Sveta, I came foryou.
I got money. Can we leave?
Quiet, Pavel, quiet.
We'll take care of you.
- Sveta!
- I told you to leave.
Don't come here anymore.
I don't love you.
It's okay, Pavel.
Everything's going to be fine.
I brought you an album.
This money... since you got it...
give some... for treatment.
You see how it is...
You said it: the city is a force.
And here everyone's weak.
The city is a dark force. The strong
come here and become weak.
The city takes our strength.
And now you've fallen.
Here, take this.
What's the problem? Take it. There's
a lot here. You'll live for a while.
What's good for the Russian
is death forthe German.
Okay, German, so long.
Thank you.
Guys, have you seen Kat?
Look in McDonalds.
If it's because of the dough, you're
wasting your time. I didn't take it.
-What are you going to do?
- I don't know.
I may go to the Pyramid, or to the
Planetarium, only it's expensive.
Penkin's playing today.
Right now it's too early to think.
Pinocchio, dish out sixty thousand.
We'll each take a hit of acid.
And in the evening I'll treat you.
I'm leaving town.
What did you want then?
- To say goodbye.
-Well, later.
Take it. Go see the Penkin concert.
What's this for?
Is this for me or something?
Okay, later.
Maybe you need something?
Well, I'm outta here?
I haven't sat out my discharge yet.
Where did you serve?
In HQ there, I sat out my hitch
as a clerk, you know...
And what do you want to be?
Me? Don't know.
A driver.
Hey, can I switch on some music?
I haven't listened to it for awhile.
Go ahead.
The snow's really piled up, huh?
Yeah.
Where you headed?
To Moscow.